The anterior epithelium here will become
a part, here, called the cornea, you see,
the corneal epithelium, which is a mesenchymal tissue,
while the conjunctival tissue is what we call
epithelial tissue, thus a boundary layer.
Then we have what we call the anterior chamber, the
pupillary orifice.
You have three main tunics surrounding the eye.
So it's like three socks, one inside the other.
The first sock is called the sclera.
It is continuous with the cornea in front.
translucent, then you have the
limbus, then the white part.
That is the first
layer. I remove this first
sock, and now I'm left with
an important layer called the choroid.
And the choroid,
you see here, is
an extremely vascularized layer.
And this choroid continues
forward, here,
with what we call
the iris.
Iridology is a reading of the mesodermal
vascular system.
By observing the eye, you can see information about trophic changes
of the vascular type.
This is expressed in the iris, which are sensors that can store, for example,
sulfur.
You can store a lot of things.
And you can learn to read them. There is a mapping of how it will be arranged.
There will be another important relationship, which is
the ciliary processes,
and there will be a relationship
with what we call the
suspensory muscles of the iris, which we will see in detail
later to understand their
physiology.
So we see the lens,
the different chambers
that will appear, the pupillary orifice,
There a bit further,
in this choroid
with the iris, you see.
which will form an important link with what is called the
suspensory ligament.
There is also a ciliary muscle, there is an accommodation system that will
develop.
And this accommodation system is the lens called the lens,
by the ciliary muscles, with the racerata, well we will see that
later,
which will increase, change its shape.
A tiny bit of my lens, to allow the image to integrate
correctly onto the retinal plane.
First sock, the sclera.
Second sock, choroid.
Third sock, the retina.
The nerve tissue, the deepest one, which is truly the expression of the brain.
With the coloboma, which provides the pathway
for the artery and the hyaloid vessels
that will form the retinal vessels, etc.
Coloboma, do you understand what that is?
With, you see, this vestige here, and this closure that will occur.
So the retina, in fact, is the innermost layer of the eye.
And so, where does this retina come from?
Do you remember this first vesicle?
this little ball that pops out, called the primary optic vesicle,
which will make a movement like this, you see, like a
chalice, a vase.
It consists of two layers, like this, you see, an inner layer, an outer layer.
And this is where you understand what we call retinal detachment.
You can clearly see these two layers.
Well, when people have a retinal detachment,
it's this layer that develops, it’s the space between the inner
layer and the outer layer of the retina.
There will be another very thin layer here, which will be very important later, it's
what we call the pigment layer.
You'll cover that, I think, in detail tomorrow. It's the entire layer of this retina with
the pigment layer,
and what we call photoreceptors, which are of the type you...
know as cones and rods. But there's still a layer called
the ganglion cells. It's really an important layer for
information transfer
to allow transduction. It’s the conversion of a photon into electrical
energy. Change
of bitter membranes.